http://www.gulfenergyinfo.com/pages/privacy-policy

Disclosures
Confidentiality, Security and Retention of Your Personal Data
How to Access, Update and Erase Your Personal Information
Our Privacy Commitments
Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC and its affiliates (together "we") respect the privacy of every person who visits, registers with or subscribes to our websites and online publications ("you"), and are committed to ensuring a safe online experience. This privacy statement outlines the information we may collect about you in relation to your use of our websites and related publications and services ("personal data") and how we may use that personal data. We act as the controller of this personal data. It also outlines the methods by which we and our service providers may (subject to necessary consents) monitor your online behavior in order to deliver customized advertisements and marketing materials and other tailored services. This privacy statement also tells you how you can verify the accuracy of your personal data and how you can request that we delete or update it.
This Privacy Statement applies to all websites operated by us (as indicated on the relevant website) ("Sites"). For the purpose of this Privacy Statement "group company" shall mean Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC. Please note that the Sites may contain links to external sites and may contain advertisements for, and/or the opportunity for you to purchase products or services from third parties. This privacy statement does not cover the activities of such third parties, and you should consult those third party sites`privacy policies for information on how your data is used by them.
Information about us
Our principal business activities are:
Business-to-Business Publishing. We provide a range of products and services focused on oil and gas, commodities, telecoms, underground utilities, natural gas, crude oil, NGLs, liquid products, LNG, refined products, oil and gas pipeline development and underground construction and rehabilitation projects, and emerging markets including magazines, newsletters, electronic information and data
Organizers of Seminars, Conferences, Training Courses and Exhibitions for the oil and gas, underground utilities and pipeline industries
Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC Address:
United States:                                                 2 Greenway Plaza                                             Suite 1020                                                       Houston, TX 77046                                          United States
United Kingdom:14 Gray’s Inn RoadWe Work Ste 1028LondonWC1X 8HNUnited Kingdom
Collection of Personal Data
Our primary goal in collecting personal data from you is to give you an enjoyable, customized experience while allowing us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs.We collect certain personal data from you, which you give to us when using our Sites and/or registering or subscribing for our products and services. However, we also give you the option to access our Sites' home pages without subscribing or registering or disclosing your personal data.Please note that we do not intend to collect any personal data from children under thirteen years of age and no child under thirteen should submit any personal data to any of the Sites. Should we discover that any such personal data has been delivered to any of the Sites, we will remove that information as soon as possible.
Types of Personal Data Held and its Use
1. Customer Services and Administration
At some Sites, Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC collects personal data, such as your name, job title, work and/or home address, and telephone number and email address in order to register you for access to certain content and subscriptions. If you do not provide this information, we may not be able to register you and allow you to access content or subscriptions. This information may be supplemented with demographic information from your use of our Sites such as your postal area, age, gender , purchasing preferences and interests. We may also collect limited personal identifying information as required by the independent auditor of certain Company publications.
At other Sites, Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC will only collect broad demographic information for aggregate use.
This information is used:
to administer and deliver to you the products and/or services you have requested in line with our obligations under the Terms and Conditions;
to operate our Sites efficiently and improve our service to you; and
to retain records of our business transactions and communications.
Where use of your personal data is not required to meet specific obligations to you, we use it on the basis that it is necessary to meet our interests in running our business efficiently and providing the best service to our users.
2. Monitoring use of our Sites
Where, as part of our Site services, we enable you to post information or materials on our Site, we process information which you upload or input, including in any password-protected sections. Subject to any necessary consents required by applicable local law, we also monitor and/or record the different Sites you visit and actions taken on those Sites, e.g. content viewed or searched for. If you are a registered user (e.g. a subscriber or taking a trial), when you log on, this places a cookie on your machine. This enables your access to content and services that are not publicly available. Once you are logged on, the actions you take - for example, viewing an article - will be recorded (subject to any necessary consents required by applicable law). We may use technology or a service provider to do this for us. This information may be used for one or more of the following purposes:
to fulfill our obligations to you in line with our obligations under the Terms and Conditions;
to improve the efficiency, quality and design of our Sites and services;
to see which articles, features and services are most read and used
to track compliance with our terms and conditions of use, e.g. to ensure that you are acting within the scope of your user license;
for marketing purposes (subject to your rights to opt-in and opt-out of receiving certain marketing communications) - see paragraph 3 below;
for advertising purposes, although the information used for these purposes does not identify you personally. Please see paragraph 5 below for more details;
to protect or comply with our legal rights and obligations; and
to enable our journalists to contact and interact with you online in connection with any content you may post to our Sites.
Where not required to meet specific legal or contractual obligations, we use personal data to meet our legitimate interests in running our business, which may include marketing and advertising, to understand the types of content our users prefer, and to defend our legal rights.
Please see paragraph 5 below for more information on cookies and similar technologies and a link to a page where you can turn them on or off. You can object to any of our other uses of your personal data by contacting us using the contact details set out below.
3. Marketing:
Some of your personal data collected under paragraphs 1 and 2 above may be used by us and/or our other group companies to contact you by email, fax, telephone and/or post for sending information or promotional material on our products and/or services and/or those of our other group companies and industry specific companies outside our group to contact you by email and/or post about their products/services. Where required by law, we will only send these marketing materials with your prior consent.Every marketing email from Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC subsidiaries contains instructions on how to opt out of receiving further marketing emails from the Company, by clicking on the “unsubscribe/email preference center” link in each email, and will in certain circumstances need to obtain your consent before sending such communications to you. If you have provided Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC subsidiaries with contact information, you can manage how we use your information by accessing our Preference Center. You may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of our marketing emails. Additionally, you can unsubscribe here or by contacting us using the details below.Further detail can be found on the applicable Site and in each marketing communication sent by us, our group companies or service providers. See also "Consents and opt-outs" section below.
Right to Object to Automated Decision TakingYou have the right to object to automated decisions being taken about you in relation to important matters that significantly affect you. If we receive a written request from any person exercising this right, we will respond within 21 days of receipt of the request and inform the individual of the steps that we intend to take to comply with the request.
4. Trading in Personal Data:
Some of your personal data may be collected and processed with the intention of selling it to other organizations, but this will not be done unless you have given your consent (separately to this privacy statement).
5. Cookies and similar technologies
All our Sites use cookies and similar technical tools to collect information about your access to the Site and the services we provide.
Cookies are pieces of information which include a unique reference code that a website transfers to your device to store and sometimes track information about you. A number of cookies we use last only for the duration of your web session and expire when you close your browser. Other cookies are used to remember you when you return to the Site and will last for longer. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. They are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie.
We may use cookies to meet our business interests in understanding how people use our Sites, carrying out advertising and providing services you request to:
remember that you have used the Site before; this means we can identify the number of unique visitors we receive to different parts of the Site. This allows us to make sure we have enough capacity for the number of users that we get and make sure that the Site runs fast enough;
remember your login session so you can move from one page to another within the Site;
store your preferences or your user name and password so that you do not need to input these every time you visit the Site;
customize elements of the layout and/or content of the pages of Site for you;
record activity on our Sites so that we understand how you use our Sites enabling us to better tailor our content, services and marketing to your needs;
collect statistical information about how you use the Site so that we can improve the Site; and
use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) or other first-party identifiers, and third-party cookies (such as Google advertising cookies) or other third-party identifiers together to target relevant ads to you on external sites using AdWords and DoubleClick Bid Manager; and
gather information about the pages on the Site that you visit, and also other information about other websites that you visit, so as to place you in a “market segment”. This information is only collected by reference to the IP address that you are using, but does include information about the county and city you are in, together with the name of your internet service provider. This information is then used to place interest-based advertisements on the Site which it is believed will be relevant to your market segment. For more information about this type of interest based advertising, and about how to turn this feature off please visit www.youronlinechoices.com or follow the links to the websites of our advertising partners shown here. (Please email us at Privacy@GulfEnergyInfo.com if you have any queries about cookies)
Some of the cookies used by our Sites are set by us, and some are set by third parties who are delivering services (such as interest based advertising directed at your market segment) on our behalf.
To see a list of the cookies and similar technologies used on this Site and instructions on how to turn them on and off click here. (Please email us at Privacy@GulfEnergyInfo.com if you have any queries about cookies)
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can change your browser to prevent that or to notify you each time a cookie is set. You can also learn more about cookies in general by visiting www.allaboutcookies.org which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browser. Please note however, that by blocking, deleting or turning off cookies used on the Site you may not be able to take full advantage of the Site.
Email tracking: So that we can better understand our users` needs, we track responses to our emails - for example, to see which links are the most popular in newsletters, and to log and follow up responses to our marketing messages. To do this, we use pixel GIFs, also known as "pixel tags" - these are small image files that are placed within the body of our email messages. They enable us to tell if a message has been opened and to track click-throughs on links within the message. Any other purposes for which Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC wishes to use your personal data will be notified to you and your personal data will not be used for any such purpose without obtaining your prior consent.
Consents and opt-outs
Where you have given your consent to particular uses or disclosures of your data, the placement of cookies or receiving marketing messages, you can withdraw that consent by:
Indicating at the point on the relevant Site where personal data is collected;
Informing us by email, post or phone; or
Updating your preferences on the applicable Site;
For turning cookies and similar technologies on and off, see the information in paragraph 5 above.
Events (Consents and opt-outs)
Photography. By submitting registration details, delegates agree to allow Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC and its associated brands to contact them regarding their services. Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC retains the irrevocable and unrestricted right to reproduce photographs and/or video images taken at its events for the purposes of promotion, illustration, advertising, or trade, in any manner and in any medium. Delegates will not be compensated for image usage; however, delegates who do not wish to have their likeness or image used in promotional or marketing materials should email privacy@gulfenergyinfo.com prior to or during the event and include ‘Event Photography Opt-out” in the email subject line. Sponsors/Exhibitors. By registering for events hosted by Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC and its subsidiary brands, delegates are agreeing to share their registration information with the event’s corporate sponsors. By submitting personal registration information, delegates are agreeing that Gulf and the event’s corporate sponsors may contact them. If registrants do not wish to share their contact information with the event’s corporate sponsors, registrants should email Privacy@GulfEnergyInfo.com stating the name of the event in the subject line and the withdrawal of consent.
Here is a link to the full Events Terms & Conditions.
Disclosures
Information collected at one Site may be shared between Gulf Publishing Holdings, LLC and any other Gulf Publishing Holdings, LLC subsidiaries for the purposes listed above.
Your personal data may also be sold to other companies in the form of lists and directories, but only after permission from you in accordance with the provisions above.
We may also disclose your personal data to certain parties , including, without limitation, professional advisers, or governmental or State institutions or regulatory authorities, where necessary in order to exercise or defend legal rights or where required by law. Where applicable, permissions are granted, we may send targeted third-party emails from industry specific organizations and group.
We may transfer, sell or assign any of the information described in this policy to third parties as a result of a sale, merger, consolidation, change of control, transfer of assets or reorganization of our business.
Public forums, message boards and blogs
Some of our Sites make message boards, blogs or other facilities for user generated content available and users can participate in these facilities. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should always be careful when deciding to disclose your personal information.
Transfers outside the EEA
Services on the Internet are accessible globally so collection and transmission of personal data is not always limited to one country. Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC may transfer your personal data, for the purposes listed above, to other group companies, service providers or other third parties which may be located in countries outside the European Economic Area, whose laws may not give the level of protection to personal data as within the UK. This will include transfers to Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC in the US and to third parties who provide us with email and marketing services. Where we conduct any transfers we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Statement, which may include putting in place contractual commitments which have been approved under EU law.
Confidentiality, Security and Retention of Your Personal Data
We are committed to keeping the data you provide us secure and will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal data from loss, misuse or alteration.
The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features described above to try to prevent unauthorized access.
We have implemented information security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from:
unauthorized access
improper use or disclosure
unauthorized modification
unlawful destruction or accidental loss
All our employees, contractors and data processors (i.e. those who process your personal data on our behalf, for the purposes listed above), who have access to, and are associated with the processing of your personal data, are obliged to keep the information confidential and not use it for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for us.
We also give you the option of using a secure transmission method to send us personal data identifiers, such as credit card details and bank account number.
We retain your personal data for as long as we have a relationship with you (e.g. for as long as you are a subscriber to any marketing materials or as long as you have an account with us). We retain your personal data for a period after our relationship with you has ended. When determining how long this period lasts, we take into account how long we may need personal data to comply with our legal obligations or with the expectations of regulators (including data protection authorities in the EU), we also take account of how long we may need information for audit purposes and to ensure we can exercise our legal rights and defend claims on the basis of limitation periods in jurisdictions in which we operate.
How to Access, Update and Erase your Personal Information
If you wish to know whether we are keeping personal data about you, or if you have an inquiry about our privacy policy or wish to exercise your rights (including, subject to applicable law, the right to access your personal date, the right to have personal data corrected or deleted, the right to restrict our use of personal data, the right to object to our uses of personal data, and the right to have personal data transmitted in electronic form to you or a third party) over your personal data , in relation to any of the Sites, you can contact the Data Protection Officer  via:
Postal mail to this address:
United States: Data Protection Officer, Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC, PO Box 2608, Houston, TX 77252
United Kingdom: Data Protection Officer, The Petroleum Economist Ltd, WeWork, 14 Grays Inn Road, London, WC1X 8HN, UK
Telephone:
United States: +1 (713) 529-4301
United Kingdom: +44 (0)20 3409 2245
Email: Privacy@GulfEnergyInfo.com
We may require proof of your identity before actioning any request.
Changes to this Privacy Statement
We will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect new legislation or industry practice, group company changes and customer feedback. We encourage you to review this Privacy Statement periodically to be informed of how we are protecting your personal data.
This Privacy Statement was last updated in May 2018.
Copyright © 2020 Gulf Publishing Holdings LLC. All Rights Reserved.
All material subject to strictly enforced copyright laws.
Please read our Terms & Conditions,
Cookies Policy and
Privacy Policy before using the site.
